Clint Eastwood will turn you Every Which Way But Loose
Every Which Way but Loose is a action, comedy,
adventure film directed by James Fargo.
Philo Beddoe is your regular, easygoing, truck-driving guy.
He's also the best bar-room brawler west of the Rockies.
And he lives with a 165-pound orangutan named Clyde.
Like other guys, Philo finally falls in love - with a flighty singer who
leads him on a screwball chase across the American Southwest.
Nothing's in the way except a motorcycle gang, some
cops, and legendary brawler Tank Murdock.
Philo Beddoe, played by Clint Eastwood.
Lynn Halsey-Taylor, played by Sondra Locke.
Orville Boggs, played by Geoffrey Lewis.
Clyde, played by Manis.
Echo, played by Beverly D'Angelo.
Tank Murdock, played by Walter Barnes.
Every Which Way but Loose is a 1978 American action
comedy film released by Warner Bros.
starring Clint Eastwood in an uncharacteristic and offbeat comedy role.
It was produced by Robert Daley and directed by James Fargo.
Eastwood plays Philo Beddoe, a trucker and bare-knuckle brawler roaming the American West in search of a
lost love while accompanied by his brother/manager Orville and his pet orangutan Clyde.
Philo encounters a wide assortment of characters, including a pair of police
officers and a motorcycle gang who pursue him for revenge.
Eastwood's appearance in the film, after his string of Spaghetti Western and Dirty Harry roles,
somewhat startled the film industry, and he was reportedly advised against taking the role.
Although it was poorly reviewed by critics, the film proved successful and became, along with its
1980 sequel Any Which Way You Can, two of the highest-grossing Eastwood films.
When adjusted for inflation, it ranks as one of the top
250 highest-grossing films of all time.
The film explores themes of martial arts, waitress,
bare knuckle boxing, fight, overweight.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.